In certain cases, you might want to change not
在某些情况下 你可能不仅想
just the access limits of your plots, but it's scaling.
修改图表的坐标轴范围 还想调整其标尺
The standard assumption is that your data should be interpreted
通常情况下 我们会对数据进行线性分析
linearly with differences being the most salient points of attention.
重点考察数据的差异性
In other cases, you might be interested in differences in terms of ratios or percentages.
但有时候 你想观察的是数据比例或百分比的差异
The classic example of a variable that might require
要用其它标尺来表示的变量
a different scale is data dealing with finance.
最典型的莫过于金融数据了
Consider this hypothetical plot of vehicle prices.
来看这个虚构的汽车价格图
Variables like this tend to have a range that crosses many orders of magnitude,
这类变量的范围往往会跨越多个数量级
and are usually skewed to the right.
而且通常会向右偏斜
With bins of size 10,000 on a linear scale,
若设其线性标尺的组距为 1 万
we end up with an unevenly balanced plot with
我们就会得到一个极不平衡的统计图
a lot of gaps in order to capture the highest values points.
为了囊括最高值的数据点 图上出现了许多空隙
If we have a linear model in mind,
考虑一下线性模型
it may be difficult for a predictor variable to capture small differences at
我们就知道预测变量很难同时兼顾标尺刻度值较小、差异较小的变量
the low end of the scale at the same time as large distances on the high end.
以及刻度值较大、数据间隔也较大的变量
The transformation that we apply in this case is a logarithmic scaling.
因此 我们需要进行变换 将标尺改为对数标尺
So the distances on the scaled axis represent
使坐标轴上的距离
multiplicative differences rather than arithmetic differences.
表示倍数差而非算术差
In this plot, the values in each bar are about
在这个图表中 每一组的值都要比
25 percent larger than the values in the previous bar.
前一组的值大 25% 左右
Instead of the tick marks increasing by adding 40,000 to the previous,
前后刻度的差也不再是 4 万了
each tick mark is twice the value of the previous.
现在后一个刻度是前一个刻度的两倍
One common distribution that results from this As the log-normal distribution,
这种标尺通常会形成一种分布 对数正态分布
where the data looks approximately normal shaped after a log transform.
此时 数据在经过对数变换后 看起来很像正态分布
This plot suggests that building a model for the logarithm of prices might work better.
由此图可见 为价格建立对数模型效果更佳
Under this transformation, linear changes in
使用该变换 预测变量的线性变化
predictor features will result in multiplicative effects in the price.
会造成价格出现倍增效应
You'll see this again in the next lesson regarding bi-variate plots.
下一节课 讲解双变量图表时 我们还会再讲这个图
Note as well that all the values in a variable
注意 变量里的所有值
must be positive in order to use a log transform.
都必须为正值 否则无法使用对数变换
If we were to continue to the left,
如果我们在坐标轴上继续往左移动
the values would continue to be divided by two.
数值就会继续被 2 除
But no matter how far we go we will never reach zero or any negative number.
但无论多左 坐标永远不会为 0 或为负值
Axis transformations are useful because they allow you to
坐标轴变换很实用
interpret your data with their naturally recording units.
借助这类变换 你就可以根据数据本身的记录单位进行分析了
For example, an alternative approach we could have taken could
举个例子 我们其实可以
have been to start by applying the transformation directly to the data.
先把数据变换了再说
When we plot the transfer of data on a linear scale,
把经过变换的数据绘制在线性标尺上
we get the same picture as the original data plotted on a log scale.
与将原始数据绘制在对数标尺上的效果是一样的
However, to interpret the values,
但到了解释数据的时候
we would need to mentally apply the inverse transformation.
我们就得在脑海中把变换后的数据恢复原样
Most people would not understand that tend to the power of 4.6 is the same as 40,000.
而大多数人都很难理解 10 的 4.6 次方其实就是 4 万
While we will need to transform the data when it comes to the analysis step,
虽然在分析时我们都需要变换数据
for visualization, it's best to stick with axis transformations.
但单从可视化界面的效果来看 还是变换坐标轴为好